Coons, Lillian; Papers ua802.011
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Lillian Coons Papers
1935-2019
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua802.011
1.5 cubic ft.
Schoolwork and scrapbooks from Lillian Coons's time at the State College for Teachers (1935-1939) where she was a member of Phi Delta and studied English, Social Studies, and Library Science.
Content Description
Contains five scrapbooks, along with photos, schoolwork, and ephemera from the State College for Teachers between the years 1935-1941. Contents include letters, personal notes, postcards, newspaper clippings, graded exams, poems, programs, pamphlets, class schedules, and drawings.
Biographical / Historical
Lillian Coons was born Lillian Elizabeth Hines in 1918 in Poland, NY. She attended the State College for Teachers from 1935-1940 where she was a member of Phi Delta. She completed a BA in English and Social Studies and a BS in Library Science. She married Earl Coons of Delanson, NY in 1941. She worked as a librarian in Ilion High School in Ilion, NY (1940-1942), then as a Typist in Camp Stewart, GA (1943) before returnng to Ilion Elementary School (1961-1962) and as a Librarian in Poland Central School (1962-1967) and Ilion High School (1967-1982). She died of colon cancer in 1991.
Arrangement
Maintained the order of the collection, unless Preservation would like to do something else to the scrapbooks.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
All items in this collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Lillian Coon's son William Coons in 2019.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; Scrapbooks; College students--New York (State)--Albany; College sorority members; Letters; Postcards; Drawings; theater programs; Pamphlets; Clippings, newspaper; Poems
- Lillian Coons's Freshman Year Scrapbook, 1935-1936
  Scope and Contents
  First volume scrapbook from the Lillain Coons collection. Created by Lillain during her Freshman year, containing schoolwork, pamphlets, programs, letters, personal notes, and newspaper clippings.
- Lillian Coons's Sophmore Year Scrapbook, 1936-1937
  Second volume scrapbook from the Lillain Coons collection. Created by Lillain during her Sophomore year, containing schoolwork, pamphlets, programs, letters, personal notes, and newspaper clippings.
- Lillian Coons's Junior Year Scrapbook, 1937-1938
  Third volume scrapbook from the Lillain Coons collection. Created by Lillain during her Junior year, containing schoolwork, pamphlets, programs, letters, personal notes, postcards, a felted sign, and newspaper clippings.
- Lillian Coons's Senior Year Scrapbook, 1938-1939
- Lillian Coons's Graduate School Scrapbook, 1939-1940
- Freshman Year Composition Book, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- N.Y. State College for Teachers Cloth Shield (Box 1, Folder 2)
- LB Cloth Patch (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Biographical Materials, 1936; 1991; 2019 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Phi Delta Photograph and Member List (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photographs, 1935-1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Essays, ca. 1935/1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Lunch to Follow," Verses Writtend For English 26 In the First Term, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Narrative Noteboook, Lillian Hines English 19, 1938 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)